Even if you’re a couch potato like me, you’ll know the benefits of running - pounding the pavements, working up a sweat, burning off some calories and generally keeping fit.
即使你和我一样是个不爱动的懒人，也一定知道跑步的好处——沿着人行道奋力奔跑、挥洒汗水、燃烧卡路里，还能全面保持身体健康。
But if you’re a real fitness junkie, the ultimate running challenge is to take part in a marathon.
但如果你是个不折不扣的健身爱好者，那跑步运动的终极挑战就是参加马拉松比赛。
It seems every major city and town around the world hosts an annual marathon, with thousands of athletes running a gruelling 42.1 kilometres.
似乎全球每个主要城镇都会举办一场年度马拉松比赛，数千名运动员要跑完这段折磨人的42.1公里赛程。
Whilst many runners’ motivation is to beat their personal best and cross the finishing line without collapsing, they’re also doing it for a good cause – to generate funds for charity.
许多跑者的动力是刷新个人最好成绩，并且能坚持着冲过终点线，同时他们参赛也是为了一项公益事业——为慈善机构募集资金。
But like other major events, the marathon also generates a massive carbon footprint.
但和其他大型活动一样，马拉松比赛也会产生巨量的碳足迹。
Thousands travel - some by plane - to the location, and waste from food packaging and goody bags gets left behind by spectators and runners.
数千人会前往举办地，其中一些人还会搭乘飞机，观众和跑者会留下大量食品包装和礼品袋产生的垃圾。
For example, during the London Marathon in 2018, 47,000 plastic bottles were collected, although some were recycled.
例如在2018年伦敦马拉松赛事期间，工作人员清理出了47000个塑料瓶，不过其中一部分得到了回收利用。
This is becoming a big issue for cities – how to host a worthwhile event, encouraging people to exercise and help charities, whilst protecting the environment?
如何举办一场有意义的赛事，既能鼓励人们锻炼身体、助力慈善，又能保护环境？这正成为许多城市面临的一大难题。
Several cities have developed formal plans to reduce their environmental impact and promote sustainable ideas.
已有多个城市制定了正式计划，以降低赛事对环境的影响，推广可持续理念。
One event in Wales, for example, introduced recycling for old running kit and ethically sourced the race t-shirts.
例如威尔士的一场马拉松赛事，就推出了旧跑步装备回收项目，并且比赛T恤的原料都来自符合道德标准的采购渠道。
It’s something that this year’s London Marathon tried to tackle by reducing the number of drink stations on the running route, giving out water in paper cups and offering some drinks in edible seaweed capsules.
今年的伦敦马拉松也尝试着手解决这个问题，赛事方减少了赛道上饮水站的数量，饮用水改用纸杯盛放，部分饮品还采用了可食用的海藻胶囊包装。
They also trialled new bottle belts made from recycled plastic so 700 runners could carry water bottles with them during their run.
赛事还试用了由回收塑料制成的新型水壶腰带，供700名跑者在比赛时随身携带水壶。
London Marathon event director Hugh Brasner told the BBC: "There's a raft of initiatives we are using this year that we think will lead to some huge behavioural changes in the future."
伦敦马拉松赛事总监休·布拉斯纳在接受BBC采访时表示：“我们今年采用了一系列举措，相信这些举措未来会带来巨大的行为转变。”
Meanwhile, some people still think running a marathon could be our best foot forward in helping the planet.
与此同时，一些人仍然认为，跑马拉松或许是我们为保护地球迈出的关键一步。
Dr Andrea Collins from Cardiff University told the BBC: "Training for a marathon makes you more sustainable in day-to-day activities.
卡迪夫大学的安德里亚·柯林斯博士告诉BBC：“为马拉松备战训练，会让你在日常生活中更倾向于选择可持续的生活方式。
I started walking or running to work every day and shunning public transport altogether.
我开始每天步行或跑步上班，完全不再乘坐公共交通工具。
Being environmentally friendly while training kind of sticks with you and becomes a way of life."
训练期间养成的环保习惯会慢慢融入你的生活，最终变成一种生活常态。”
So while you may not be the elite runner in a marathon, let’s hope the event, in terms of sustainability, certainly is!
所以，即便你可能不是马拉松赛场上的精英跑者，也希望这项赛事能在可持续发展方面做到尽善尽美。